(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone and
welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco and my name is Katherine.
So as usual, we've got a great
dialogue for you today and
before we get going, I should
mention what the topic is.
So Marco, take it away.
- We are actually having
a small fight at the office.
Somebody or a co-worker is annoying us.
So sometimes co-workers,
you see them every day.
They're doing something that's
maybe getting on your nerves.
- And you practically live
together because you're
with each other for eight,
nine, 10 hours every day.
- Exactly.
So that's what we're gonna be looking at
today, some language related to this topic.
So let's listen to the
dialogue for the first time.
(upbeat music)
- Hey Mary, can you cut that out?
- Cut what out?
I'm not doing anything.
- The tapping of your pen on your desk.
It's driving me crazy.
- Fine.
By the way, would you mind not slurping
your coffee every time you have a cup?
- I don't slurp my coffee.
And plus, how can you hear it when you're
shouting into your phone all the time?
- You've got to be kidding me.
You're complaining about
me talking on the phone.
When you go out for a cigarette
break, 10 times a day to shoot the breeze.
- Look, we have a lot of accumulated
anger from working in these conditions.
And it's probably okay to
let off steam once in a while.
But it's probably not a
good idea to keep it up.
I'm willing to forgive
and forget if you are.
- Fine.
Let's call it truth.
I'll try to be more considerate
and keep the noise down.
- Yeah, I'll try to do the same.
So I was wondering, do we want
to go out to dinner Friday night?
- Ah, ah, ah.
- All right, we're back.
So yeah, I think this is a
common situation, right?
So common, this might even
be based on our own lives.
(laughing)
- It is, you may not know, but
Catherine, I get into fights all the time.
- All the time.
- No, not really.
- All right, so I think there was some
interesting words here, but mostly phrases.
So let's start with the words
first on language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- All right, so the first
word as you might
have guessed has to do
with eating and drinking.
This is called slurping
and it's some lirp to slurp.
So the noun, the thing is
slurping and it's very common
with people who eat their food quickly.
- Like soup.
- Yeah, soup or you know, or
when they're eating soup noodles.
- Or sometimes when you have a drink
and you're drinking it through a straw,
towards the end, you're just like trying
to get the very last part at the bottom.
So yeah, the straw slurps.
- Yeah, so slurping, some
people really can't stand it
and sometimes you don't
even notice that you're doing it.
- No, absolutely not.
- All right, so apart from
slurping, what else do we have?
- We've got a great word here, accumulated.
So a lot of accumulated anger.
The word is a verb to accumulate.
- And what does that mean?
- It means to kind of grow
or to become more and more.
All right, so you're saving it.
- Or even it's like building
up, you know, we say this will
oftentimes in Chicago where
it snows a lot in the winter,
that there's a foot of snow
accumulated on the ground.
That means there's a lot of snow and every
time it snows, it keeps getting bigger.
Yeah, so to accumulate.
- So accumulated anger, your
anger is getting bigger and bigger.
- Right, 'cause you never
tell anyone about your anger.
So it keeps building
and it keeps piling up.
- All right, well, towards the end,
they said, well, let's call it truth.
So they wanna call it truth.
All right, a truth is
another word for a peace.
And so this is a way
that you can stop fighting
and say that you and I have
been fighting for a long time,
we may not come to a deal, but we'll
say truth from now on, we just won't fight.
- We'll fight about it, okay.
- Brothers and sisters often call truth.
- That's true.
- And well, if you're calling a truth,
you're trying to be more considerate.
- Okay, considerate, like you're saying,
is a way to be or a way
to act and considerate,
often has to do with how
you act towards other people.
So it's being nice to other people or
thinking about other people's feelings
before you're yourself.
- All right, so if you're considerate,
then you are maybe more polite.
You think about the other person's
feelings before you do anything.
- It's like, well, you
just say nice little
things like please and
thank you and I'm sorry.
And these things are all
ways of being considerate.
- Very good.
All right, so for great
words on language takeaway,
why don't we move on
now to fluency builder?
- Fluency builder.
- All right, so as we
mentioned, this dialogue
is very, very rich in a
lot of different phrases.
So let's start with a couple of them.
The very first one and the title of
the lesson, cut it out, cut that out.
- Hey Mary, can you cut that out?
- Right, so you're not actually saying
to cut something with
scissors or something.
- No, this is, it's a way of
saying, can you stop that?
- Stop it, stop doing that.
- Stop it, quit it.
- Okay, cut that out, cut it out.
- So if someone's doing something
that's really annoying to
you, it's not very nice to say,
but you can say, hey,
cut that out, cut it out.
Or if someone's doing something
mean to someone, like my
brother used to hit me, my
mom would say, Peter, cut that out.
- All right, so it is a
good mom phrase as well.
All right, moving on to our next phrase,
the guy said that the tapping on the desk
was driving him crazy,
it's driving me crazy.
- All right, to drive someone crazy means
to make someone just
feel like they're going nuts.
Or just, it makes you kind of
angry or frustrated or tense.
- But it can also be used
in a romantic sense, right?
That girl drives me crazy.
- It means like, he can't even
think about anything else.
- All right.
- So in this case, what drives you crazy?
- When, I'll tell you what drives me crazy,
when people clip their fingernails
and toenails, at the office, can't believe.
Well, it drives me crazy, like for example,
when somebody or my
brother leaves his clothes lying
on the floor in the
living room, for example.
- That's annoying too.
- Yeah.
- So that drives me crazy.
All right, so moving
on to our third phrase,
this is a pretty big one,
but take it as a whole.
You've got to be kidding me.
- All right, so this is, as you said,
a fixed phrase, these
words usually go together
and it is a perfect
example of sarcasm.
So it's a way, the way
you say it is very important.
So I could say, you've
got to be kidding me.
What's a good situation for this?
Maybe I get to the
airport and I'm running late
and I'm really happy
that I get there on time
and then I see the flight
is delayed seven hours.
- Exactly.
- You've got to be kidding me.
- Right, so it's always
saying I can't believe it
or seriously this isn't,
yeah, what's happening?
- What bad luck.
- Right, so it is a sarcasm
phrase, but use it as a whole.
Usually you don't change the subject.
You don't say, you've
got to be kidding him.
- No, it's always this.
You've got to be kidding me.
- All right.
- Or you've got to be kidding me.
See, different meanings
with different inflexions.
- Different inflexions.
- Very good.
What's our next phrase?
- Our next phrase is a good one because
it doesn't mean what it sounds like.
Okay, so to shoot the
breeze, all right, shoot means
like you can shoot a gun
and breeze is like the wind.
But here, to shoot the
breeze is to have a nice
little conversation just
to talk about nothing.
- Okay, so I'm not really do anything.
Just talk a little bit.
- Right, so if we think
about this in the context
of this sentence, it's,
you know, you go out
for your cigarette break 10
times a day to shoot the breeze.
So this means you go
outside and you just talk
about nothing and whatever and it's almost
like you're wasting time just talking.
- Okay, so shooting the breeze.
You can say, oh, we were
just shooting the breeze.
- We just have a nice little conversation.
Nothing important.
- Okay, and our last phrase
for today, forgive and forget.
Let's forgive and forget.
- Let's forgive and forget.
This is, these words again like the last
phrases, go together, forgive and forget.
So I could say this to you, Marko, I say,
I know you've been fighting
with your brother for 10 years.
I say, finally, just forgive and forget.
I mean, just put everything
behind you and try and start again.
- Okay, let it go.
- Yeah, forgive the person,
forget about it, move on.
- Okay, forgive and forget.
Very good.
So very interesting phrases, I think.
They're very useful and this is
very colloquial English, right?
- Absolutely.
This is stuff that you're
gonna hear all the time,
but maybe not all
together at the same time.
Definitely though, very
helpful for interacting
with foreign friends and colleagues.
- Very good.
So let's listen to the dialogue for
the last time and we'll be right back.
(upbeat music)
- Hey, Mary, can you cut that out?
- Cut what out?
I'm not doing anything.
- The tapping of your pen on your desk.
It's driving me crazy.
- Fine.
By the way, would you mind not slurping
your coffee every time you have a cup?
- I don't slurp my coffee.
And plus, how can you hear it when you're
shouting into your phone all the time?
- You've got to be kidding me.
You're complaining about
me talking on the phone.
- When you go out for a cigarette break,
10 times a date of shoot their breeze.
- Look, we have a lot of accumulated
anger from working in these conditions
and it's probably okay to
let off steam once in a while,
but it's probably not a
good idea to keep it up.
I'm willing to forgive
and forget if you are.
- Fine, let's call it truth.
I'll try to be more considerate
and keep the noise down.
- Yeah, I'll try to do the same.
So I was wondering, do you want
to go out to dinner right at night?
(baby crying)
(upbeat music)
- So do you ever see the TV show
full house when you were a kid?
- I did, I did, it was a couple of times.
(laughing)
- With the Olsen twins
and all those, right?
- Yeah, and Bob Sagitt.
So there was an uncle
on the show, Uncle Joey.
And he always used to say cut it out.
And he had like hand motions for it.
And so cut it out as a way
to say kind of stop it, quit it.
You're killing me, it's like
he was saying too funny.
- Right, right.
- And so whenever I hear this phrase,
I always think of that early 90s show.
- Very early 90s, yeah.
- Well, this whole situation
with the office as well,
I think there was a TV
show called The Office, right?
- Yeah, there was the British office
and then there was an American version.
- And it's also something about office life
and how colleagues get on
each other's nerves and they
play pranks on each other
and everyone's kind of weird.
- And everyone drives everyone else crazy.
- Exactly.
- No, it's funny because
once you start working in an
office full time, I mean,
everyone's maybe had a little bit
of office experience,
but when it's full time,
you spend more time with your
colleagues than you do with your family.
It's really amazing what makes you crazy,
what drives you crazy and
what stuff doesn't matter.
- So this is an interesting topic.
We really wanna hear from you guys.
Many of you probably
work at an office, so tell us,
so come and tell us what drives you crazy
or maybe what colleague is driving you mad.
- You don't have to use names, you
can just use nicknames if you want.
- Right, so we'll be waiting
for you at englishpot.
com, leave questions and comments
and we'll see you guys next time.
- Yep, bye everyone. - Bye.
(upbeat music)